<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Yi-Te (Eeder) Hsu</title>
    <link>https://eederhsu.github.io/project/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://eederhsu.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>2019</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://eederhsu.github.io/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>https://eederhsu.github.io/project/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19 News Website</title>
      <link>https://eederhsu.github.io/project/covid-19-news-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eederhsu.github.io/project/covid-19-news-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our goal is to build a COVID-19 news website containing the latest and the most important local information classified by different topics and without redundant contents.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is a colossal amount of information about COVID-19 on the Internet. People are overwhelmed by considerable content and struggling to find crucial information to protect themselves. In this website, we collect information from government websites, professional news, and social media. After data collection, we applied information retrieval techniques and NLP techniques to remove redundant contents and built a system self-learning extracting critical information for each user. Furthermore, we build a website to demonstrate the information. &lt;a href=&#34;https://covid19news.herokuapp.com/&#34;&gt;https://covid19news.herokuapp.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Yelp-Dataset-Analysis</title>
      <link>https://eederhsu.github.io/project/yelp-dataset-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eederhsu.github.io/project/yelp-dataset-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are plenty of valuable information on the Yelp website. These data can be helpful after applying data science techniques. The business struggled during this pandemic, and we would like to analyze and provide insight for the business. In this project, we provide three major aspects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Business clustering and recommendation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;2&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Build a tool that helps business evaluate reputation before opening.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;ol start=&#34;3&#34;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Review analysis: Classify the positive or negative reviews by text.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Facebook Likes Estimator</title>
      <link>https://eederhsu.github.io/project/facebook-likes-estimator-for-major-news-publishers-pages-/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eederhsu.github.io/project/facebook-likes-estimator-for-major-news-publishers-pages-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The project seeks to find the factors of the numbers of likes for posts from news publisher’s Facebook page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Data are collected from the Facebook pages of major news publisher such as: The New York Times, BBC News, The Huffington Post, CNN, TIME, The Wall Street Journal, and The Economist. A parser is built to obtain the raw data, which includes total likes for the page, created time of the post, content of the post and total likes for the post. From the raw data, we extract the following features: published day (Sunday-Saturday, marked as 0-6), published time, length of post (as number of words), and the tone of the post (leveled from 0-6). The last feature is supported by the Stanford CoreNLP Natural Language Processing Toolkit. Other features to be tested are event-specific time coefficient, for example, days before Thanksgiving, and preference of terms, which will utilize Stanford CoreNLP’s ability to identify popular terms from text.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These data will be separated into train and test cases. After obtaining the features, we first used visualize method such as histogram and bar plot to gain insight into the data. Finally, applied different mining techniques, for example, decision tree, to clarify the relationship between features and like counts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In our result, we suggest a better post consist of only a few sharp sentences or a detailed paragraph. The commonly seen emoji icon and hashtag actually have no effect on the post’s popularity. Another trend we found is that post during worktime and workday receives less like.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Achieved 95% accuracy in predicting how many likes one post will obtain by machine learning techniques&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>how social media influence human emotion</title>
      <link>https://eederhsu.github.io/project/social-media-emotion/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eederhsu.github.io/project/social-media-emotion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Designed an android App to collect real-time data that tracked user happiness.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Used statistics to reveal the relationship between users happiness and the time spent on social media.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MovieWatson</title>
      <link>https://eederhsu.github.io/project/moviewatson/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2016 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eederhsu.github.io/project/moviewatson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MovieWatson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; is a light movie recommendation system for each person. Most of the movie recommendation systems need the registration of their members. In addition, these recommendation systems will recommend the movie by the historical information of this user. These are lack of flexibility. Therefore, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MovieWatson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; used instant rating, and the users can also receive the recommendation by their interests at the moment. Meanwhile, &lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MovieWatson&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; does not need users to register as a member, it saves complex registration procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Features:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Built a movie recommendation system that instantaneously captured user preference without needing user data history.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Utilized collaborative filtering system as well as database retrieval method to provide recommended 10 movies.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Speaker Identification</title>
      <link>https://eederhsu.github.io/project/speaker-recognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://eederhsu.github.io/project/speaker-recognition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This research focuses on speaker recognition, which has a variety of applications – automatic identification of the electronic device’s owner or different speakers in a conference. Collecting 20 training samples, the authors have used FFT to analyze the spectra of two different speakers and found several features in it, such as the number of the peaks that are larger than the mean amplitude. After establishing five criteria, the researchers successfully identified speakers from 10 input test data. What remains to be deeper understood includes the implementation of machine learning algorithms and the analysis of the signals in time domain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Results&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt;: Achieved 100% accuracy on identifying two speakers by performing FFT to the speech signals and utilized 5 differences between the speakers such as the number of peaks in the spectrum&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
